Jeremy Ruppel

Full-stack Software Engineer

jeremy.ruppel@gmail.com github.com/jeremyruppel Download PDF

Profile

Senior software engineer with extensive experience in all aspects of the web stack, from design to production, from architecture to scaling. Passionate about emerging technologies, best practices, and being a part of the open source community.

Skills

JavaScript ActionScript

Flash

Ruby HTML

HTML 5 Web Development

User Interface Design Agile Methodologies

User Experience Ruby on Rails

Github Git

Open Source RSpec

Node.js CoffeeScript

Test Driven Development Redis

PostgreSQL Heroku

RubyMotion Twilio

Experience

Lead Developer

March 2012 - Present

Remind101

San Francisco

Implemented message processing queue that delivers ~0.5MM messages a day with 99.99% success rate. Raised test coverage from 30% to 85%. Created auxiliary services to

reduce bloat and workload on main application.

Senior Creative Developer

July 2011 - March 2012

AKQA

San Francisco Bay Area

Developed brand and campaign experiences for clients including Target (Weekly Ad) and Red Bull (Launchpad). Tapped to prototype for new business pitches and develop internal tools.

Creative Developer

July 2010 - July 2011

AKQA

San Francisco Bay Area

Developed brand and campaign experiences for clients including Target (My Target Weekly), McDonalds (Avatar), and Gap (1969 Style Stream).

Associate Creative Developer

July 2009 - July 2010

AKQA

San Francisco Bay Area

Developed brand and campaign experiences for clients including Nike (AW77, N98), Gap (1969 Style Stream), and XBOX (various titles).

Education

Rochester Institute of Technology

2004 - 2009

BS, New Media Interactive Development, Computer Audio, Creative Writing